

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration

University of the People Distance Education in Pasadena, California, USA 3 units Completed 6 units ongoing

Bachelor of Science in Civil Engineering

Adamson University
Taft Avenue, Manila, Philippines
Year Graduated: March 1996

PROFESSION

Qatar Ministry of Environment -Engineers and Consultancy Accredited Grade: A Engineer (UPDA # 8660)

Registered Civil Engineer PRC License No.: 0077888

MEMBERSHIPS

Philippine Institute of Civil Engineers – Doha, Qatar Chapter Life member No: 7720

Project Management Institute (PMI-USA) PMI Member ID No: 1450751

Filipino Planning Engineer Association (FPEA-QATAR) Member ID No. 0471

Arold C. Delos Reyes

Sr.Civil Engineer
Mobile: +974 55982874
Email: arold73@yahoo.com

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

A self-motivated Licensed Civil Engineer professional having more than **26 years** (17 Qatar + 9 Philippine) with a remarkable experience and knowledgeable in the construction industry specializing in construction / facility management and supervision, inspection, and quality assurance/quality control works. Has been involved in the technical review/evaluation and assessment of contractor's various technical submittals such as shop drawings, method statements, material submittals, structural calculations, and prequalification documents. Has extensive knowledge in international standards and codes such as ACI, BS, ASTM, NFPA, HTM and QCS 2014. Has a wide range of experience in construction supervision and with good engineering skills, construction techniques, and methodologies a certified UPDA Engineer in Doha, Qatar with a grade 'A" classification.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Conseil Engineering Consultant – Doha, Qatar Client (Ariane Real Estate)/Construction Supervision Consultant Senior Civil/Structural Engineer, June 2021 – October 2022

JOB DESCRIPTION:

- Review of all civil and structural submittals that include but not limited to design drawings, shop drawings, method statements, material submittals, prequalification submittals etc...
- Collaborate and interact with all other disciplines in the project to ensure proper work interface and timely completion submittal's review.
- Lead and direct civil and structural inspectors and provide technical recommendations to construction issues in the project.
- Participate in the weekly progress & technical meetings with contractors and client
- Review all civil/structural inspection requests commented by inspectors and provide additional input prior to issuance to Contractor.
- Assist in the review of contractor's monthly progress report.
- Assist inspectors in the preparation and issuance of Non-Conformance Report and Site Observation Report for any works not in accordance with the project standards

PROJECTS EXPERIENCE:

Design & Supervision of Qatar Garden 133 Villas The project consist of 133 (G+1+ PH) Residential Villas with individual Boundary walls for each and separate Plot PIN Number.

Design & Supervision of - Al Thumama Complex Project - The Project consists of a mix (28) (G+1+ PH) (G+2) (G+2+ PH) Residential buildings and 2 Commercial Building with 1 Basement in the center and the whole area of the project containing swimming pool facilities building complex, parking areas, Service Rooms, Store rooms, and MEP Rooms.

Arab Engineering Bureau- Doha, Qatar

Construction Supervision Consultant

Senior Civil/Structural Engineer, July 2015 - June 2021

JOB DESCRIPTION:

- Review of all civil and structural technical submittals that include but are not limited to shop drawings, method statements, material submittals, and prequalification submittals.
- Liaise with the design team for any design issues encountered during the construction phase.
- Collaborate and interact with all other disciplines in the project to ensure proper work interface and timely
 completion submittal's review.
- Lead and direct civil and structural inspectors and provide technical recommendations to construction issues in the
 project.
- Participate in the weekly progress meeting with contractors and sub-contractors on a weekly basis.
- Review all civil/structural inspection requests commented by inspectors and provide additional input prior to issuance to Contractor.
- Assist in the review of contracts tor's monthly progress reports.
- Evaluate and measure the amount of work done and the Interim payments submitted by the contractor
- Assist inspectors in the preparation and issuance of Non-Conformance Report and Site Observation Report for any
 works not in accordance with the project standards
- Liases with Government agencies (Municipalities/Lusail Authorities, QCDD, Ashghal, Kahramaa, and Qtel, Marafeq etc.) to get approval for projehandoverver and Close out.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE:

4 Tower Residential Building(2B+G+7F), Muntazah- Doha, Qatar

Al Khaliji Bank Towers (3B+G+M+26F)- Lusail, Qatar

Beema Office Building, Energy City-Lusail, Qatar

Techno Head Qtr Building, Energy City Lusail, Qatar

Qatari Diar Head Quarters, Lusail District Qatar

Al Meera Neighbourhood Retail for Qatari Diar, Lusail

Al Malki Headquarters Building, Al Saad

Renovation & General Postal Corp for GPO - Package2, West bay Doha Qatar

49 Villa Residential Compound-, Muraik Al Rayyan

Sidra Village Staff Housing, Al Rayyan Qatar

HLG (HABTOOR-LEIGHTON GROUP) Doha, Qatar

Civil / Project Engineer July 2005- July 2015

A Dubai based General Contractor Company that builds, commercial building, hospitals, wharf age, airports, coastal restoration, and high-rise hotels. And it is now on major expansion in Doha, Qatar.

JOB DESCRIPTION:

- Responsible for the overall project implementation & supervision from civil works to tower erection.
- Provide technical advice to sub-contractor for any construction issues that arises at site.
- Assist in evaluating subcontractors billing on a monthly basis.
- Inspect and monitor sub-contractors works daily and report directly to the Project Manager.
- Check quality of works and ensure that the he works done are to the highest quality and workmanship.
- Review and approve method statement of sub-contractor prior to commencing works at site.
- Review and approve As-Built drawings of the project and submit to client.
- Attend/witness testing of samples such as concrete cylinders, reinforcing bars and other construction materials
 used at site and ensure all results conforms to the requirements in the approved shop drawings and project
 specifications.
- · Prepare and update construction schedule of the project and ensure that all deadlines are meet on schedule.
- Attend hand-over inspection and snagging of sub-contractor's work.
- Assist in the post permits acquisition of the project after completion.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE:

Doha City Center Expansion Phase II & III (5 towers with 3B+GRD+50Fw/PODIUM) Marriot/Rotana/Shangrila- West Bay, Doha Renovation of Hamad Hospital Bone & joint Center (2 floors Interior and parking area) Central Doha Kahramaa Warehouse and Training Centre facilities (Abu Hamour, Doha)

SUMMAKUMAGAI INC. (SKI CONSTRUCTION GROUP) Makati City, Philippines Civil / Project Engineer, June 2004 to June 2005

ISO-TUV 2001 Certified General Contractor Co. that builds, hospitals, schools and high-rise tower.

Projects:

College of St. Benilde School for Design and Arts, De La Salle Taft Avenue, Manila North Triangle Mall, Quezon City, Manila Philippines

DUTIES & RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Prepare, check and verify work procedures on high-rise building construction such as.
- Project schedules / S-curves for progress billings base on master schedule thru MS project software.
- Earthworks, backfilling and compaction, soil poisoning.
- Structural rebar works, formworks, concreting (form pile foundation to roof deck slabs)
- Structural steel installation (from Column to purlins of warehouse)
- Architectural finishes (masonry, plastering, Drywall partition, ceiling, doors, windows, and repainting works)
- Coordinate and check subcontractors and suppliers regarding their materials and manpower activities.
- Partial estimate on actual and necessary material needed at construction site prior to purchasing
- Coordinate to engineers regarding MEP works with regards to their embedded items prior to construction.
- Constant communication and coordination with regards to safety engineers regarding safety work procedures

TAISEI CORPORATION - Manila, Philippines

Civil Engineer, July 2003–December 2003

JOB DESCRIPTION:

- Monitors daily site activities and end ensures all on-going works are being executed in accordance with the approved method statement and shop drawings.
- Regularly check all works at site and ensure all required inspections as per approved Inspection test plan (ITP)
 are submitted to Consultant.
- Prepare all QA/QC related document submittals like method statements, material submittals and prequalifications of the project.
- Maintain records and photos of all site activities like concreting, removal of forms, curing and testing of concrete samples.
- Check all materials delivered to site and make sure the materials are in very good quality and consistent to approved material submittals.
- Check all works and ensure ready for inspection prior to submitting inspection to consultant.
- Issue Non-Compliance Report for any site activities being done not in accordance with the shop drawings and method statement.
- Provide technical support for any construction issues that arises at site.
- Prepare and submit proposal for closing-out NCR's issued by Consultant
- Monitors compliance of site personnel and on-going site activities to project's HSE rules and standards.

Projects:

Ajinomoto manufacturing Plant and warehouse. Guiginto, Bulacan

FLP PHILIPPINES INC Manila, Philippines

Manager Level - Independent Distributor, September 1999 - May 2003

A multi-billion-dollar Network Marketing company based in Scottsdale, Arizona, that manufactures and sells dozens of Natural Health, Beauty and Wellness Products that Started 1991 and Expanded and Boomed in the Philippines since 1996.

JOB DESCRIPTION:

- Report directly to the Senior Manager for the weekly status of network sales.
- Responsible in balancing the objectives of the company/business and for the customer satisfaction.
- Responsible in analyzing, formulation, creation market strategies through research studies and market characteristics that promotes excellent services and products.
- Helps Company to coordinate and evaluate different financial aspects such as ROI, budget, expenditures, and projection of profit and loss.
- Responsible in promoting products and marketing plans through seminars, events gathering throughout the Philippines and other countries.
- Ability to tracked and preside weekly coordination meeting to team members and client regarding outstanding issues and customer complains.

Hutama - Rsea J.o. Inc Manila, Philippines Site Engineer, March 1998 – August 1999

A Taiwanese and Indonesian joint venture contractor that construct the Metro Manila Skyway Project along South Luzon Expressway Manila, Philippines

JOB DESCRIPTION:

- Prepare, check and verify work procedures on bridge highway construction such as: Civil Infrastructure (Bored file excavation, rebar installation and concreting)
- Form works, rebar works, concreting (from Pile cap foundation to structural concrete slabs)
- Road highway finishes such as curve, gutter, railing and asphalt finishes.
- Coordinate supplier and subcontractors' workers regarding materials equipment (manpower and distribution)

EEI CORPORATION Manila, Philippines Quality Control Engineer July 1997 – March 1998

An ISO Certified General contractor that build METRORAIL TRANSIT (MRT) along EDSA HIGHWAY

JOB DESCRIPTION:

- Conducted pre -concrete pouring inspection such as alignments and grades of structures, rebar works, form works and imbedded items prior to submitting to consultant.
- Submit weekly accomplishments report and operation performance rating
- Monitor ASSHTO girder erection.
- Evaluate 3rd party laboratory material test result.
- Monitor back filling works and conducting field density test.
- Coordinate with the project in charge regarding quality and progress of work.
- Implement quality control plans and procedure.
- Check actual construction if conforms the approved plans.

EXTRAORDINARY DEV. CORPORATION (EARTH AND STYLE) Manila, Philippines Quality Control Engineer, December 1996 – July 1997

A housing developer that creates its own batching plant to support its high concrete demand.

DUTIES & RESPONSIBILITIES

- Received and check the quality of the raw materials delivered (cement, aggregates, and chemicals)
- · Initiate and testing of physical and chemical composition of concrete raw materials
- Prepare design mixes and conduct proper cylinders sampling at site
- Conduct ocular inspection through coordination with site / project engineer
- Control, check and monitor the production of Ready-Mix Concrete.
- Assist in the supervision of batching plant operation. Submit effective report, memos and recommendation to the Head Office

One story residential unit Canduling Ronda Cebu, Philippines PROJECT COORDINATOR, May - July 1996

- Design roof trusses and roof beam for the load capacity
- · Change the remodel roof design (from G.I.
- sheets to tegula roofing)
- Assist supervision on overall construction
- Make progress report as well as estimating and cost control of the project

VASQUEZ BUILDING SYSTEM Quezon City, Philippines **PROJECT COORDINATOR**, February 96- May 96

Observe and supervised on site construction of SD-2MODEL HOUSE for the WORLD BEX'95 EXHIBIT at Philippine International Convention Center.